Previously on Transformers Prime:
在上一集里
If you don't survive, Optimus, I fear neither will this planet.
万一你牺牲了 擎天柱 恐怕这星球也活不成了
No!
不！
What happened?
是谁干的？
- Wasn't me.
- 不是我 - 也不是我
I happened.
是我干的
Optimus, our past alliances--
擎天柱 我们过去的阵营
-- Autobot, Decepticon, no longer matter,
什么汽车人 霸天虎 都去他的吧
not while Unicron lives.
眼下 宇宙大帝复活了
I can lead you directly to Unicron's spark.
我能直接带你们找到宇宙大帝的火种
A truce between Autobots and Decepticon.
汽车人与霸天虎之间的停战协议
Optimus, how are we supposed to stop Unicron?
擎天柱 我们该怎么阻止宇宙大帝？
With the Martrix of Leadership.
用领导模块
It appears our leader has abandoned us.
看来统帅弃我们而去了
I believe we must consider the possibility of the future without Megatron.
我认为 我们必须做出长远的打算 无需考虑威震天了
Jack, I feel you've earned the responsibility of safeguarding this important device,
杰克 我觉得 你完全可以担当保管这个重要器物的责任
until I return.
直到我回来为止
So how long before Unicron Knows we're here?
那个…宇宙大帝何时才会发现我们？
Make no mistake. He already does.
别搞错了 他已经知道了
Unicron grows ever stronger.
宇宙大帝的力量又增强了
How do we know Unicron isn't using Megatron to lead us all into a trap?
怎么才能确定 威震天不是带我们走进宇宙大帝的陷阱？
We do not.
无法确定
More than 16 volcanoes are erupting worldwide and downtown Honolulu is under 6 inches of snow.
全世界有超过16座火山接连爆发
Scientists continued to devise theories connecting these unprecedented natural disasters with the planetary alignment which...
科学家一度推断 这些史无前例的自然灾害与星球串联之间…
So, who wants to play a game?
好了 谁想做游戏？
That tears it!
我受够了！
Where are you going?
你要去哪儿？
I can't just sit on my hands while the world spins out of control.
我不能就这么眼睁睁看着全世界失控
And what exactly is that that you intend to do?
那你究竟想干什么？
Anything.
什么都想干！
Hook up with my boys at the Pentagon, figure out a way to bury that monster for good.
叫上五角大楼的弟兄们 想办法彻底埋了那个怪物
In the event Optimus can't?
你是担心擎天柱会失败？
Don't you mean Optimus and Megatron?
你看好擎天柱和威震天联手吗？
No one here is thrilled about this arrangement, Agent Fowler, myself included.
没有人看好这种搭配 福勒探员 包括我在内
But with Optimus and Megatron together again...
可既然他们二人能再次并肩战斗…
Wow, wait, again?
喔 慢着 再次？
Megatron was an Autobot?
威震天当过汽车人？
Optimus was a 'Con?
擎天柱以前是虎子？
No, on neither count. But there was a time back on Cybertron,
不 都不是 话说 那是在很久以前的塞博特恩
in the twilight hours of the Golden Age, when Optimus and Megatron were not sworn enemies.
黄金时代尚存余辉 擎天柱和威震天还不是宿敌
Do you recall when I mentioned that Optimus wasn't always a Prime?
还记得吗？我说过 擎天柱并不一直是领袖
While, he wasn't always Optimus either.
其实 他的本名也不叫擎天柱
He was once a clerk in the Iacon Hall of Records, named Orion Pax.
当时他只是铁堡档案馆的小职员 名叫奥利安・派克斯
But as he learned more about Cybertron's past,
随着对塞博特恩历史的深入了解
he grew increasingly concerned about the present corruption in high places,
他越发关注高层人士存在的腐败问题
and inequality among the masses.
以及民众中的不平等现象
Orion became inspired by the words and ideas of a gladiator,
一个角斗士的思想言论使奥利安深受启发
one who had named himself after one of the 13 original Primes, Megatronus.
那个战士给自己冠以十三元祖领袖之一的名字 震天威
Megatronus vow to challenge Cybertron's leadership and demand that all Cybertronians be treated as equals.
震天威立誓要挑战塞博特恩的领导阶级 要求所有塞博特恩人享受平等待遇
This gladiator turned revolutionary rapidly gathered a loyal following, Soundwave chief among them.
这个角斗士振臂一呼 很快召集了一批忠实的追随者
Orion began corresponding with Megatronus who came to be something of a mentor to him.
奥利安开始和震天威来往 而后者逐渐扮演了导师的角色
As Megatronus left the gladiatorial arena for the political, he shift to shorten his name.
震天威离开了角斗场 走上政治舞台 出于私心 他改换了自己的名字
Before long, Megatron appear before the High Council to propose his vision for a just society.
不久之后 威震天在最高议会面前 提出了他所谓的公正社会构想
And it was here that he began to reveal his true colors,
从此之后 他开始露出自己真实的面目
proclaiming the need to overthrow the old goverments with force and arrogantly demanding to be named as the next Prime.
他声称 要用武力推翻陈旧的制度
But Orion did not believe in violence as a means of achieving justice.
但是 奥利安认为 不能用暴力手段来换取正义
The Sparks and minds of the Council were moved by Orion's words.
议会成员们被奥利安的真知灼见所折服
Here, for the first time since Cybertron's Golden Age, stood someone worthy of being a Prime.
此时此刻 自塞博特恩进入黄金时代以来
But that honor could only truly be achieved by earning the legendary Matrix of Leadership.
但是 要想获得那种荣耀 只有先赢取传说中的领导模块
His ambition thwarted, Megatron spitefully severed all ties with Orion and the Council,
野心落空之后 威震天愤然与奥利安和议会一刀两断
and came to wage war on all who opposed him though his growing army of followers which he named Decepticons.
并向所有对立者开战
He vow to claim the Matrix for himself wherever it might lie.
他发誓 无论模块藏在何处 都要将它据为己有
In time, warfare consumed Cybertron, poisoning the planet to its core.
后来 塞博特恩饱受战争的蹂躏 星球的核心也备受荼毒
Orion journeyed there hoping to reverse the ill effects and found himself before the very spark of our life giver, Primus himself.
奥利安进入核心 希望能使星球起死回生
The ailing Primus sensed the innate nobility within Orion and bestowed the Matrix upon him.
原始天尊在弥留之际 领会到奥利安与生俱来的高尚品质
It was thus, that a surprised and humbled Orion Pax came to be Optimus, the last of the Primes.
就这样 诚惶诚恐的奥利安・派克斯 正式更名为擎天柱 成为最后的领袖
So Optimus get the Matrix from Cybertron's core and now he's going to give it to Earth's?
这么说 擎天柱从塞博特恩的核心拿到模块 现在要把它送给地球？
What's to stop Megatron from just claiming the Matrix for himself this time around?
如果威震天这次还想把模块据为己有 我们怎么办？
Only his greater desire to save this planet so that he may in turn conquer it, as he so compellingly argued.
他拼命想保住这个星球 就是为了日后在这里称霸 这一点他供认不讳
Provided the lord of the Decepticons can never be fully trusted.
何况 霸天虎头领提出的停战协议 从来都不可全信
Unicron's spark is near.
宇宙大帝的火种就在附近
After you.
你先走
Fine, Bee. Just woozy.
没事 小蜂 只是有点头晕
The Dark Energon. It's starting to affect him. Steady as you go, Bulk.
黑暗能量已经开始影响他了 走路小心点儿 小隔
He is preparing to expel us.
他准备给我们下逐客令了
What are those things?
那是些什么东西？
As we are within Unicron's body, it stands to reason they are some sort of antibody.
我们身处宇宙大帝体内 由此可见 它们应该是某种抗体
Bee, let me go. I'll only take you down with me.
小蜂 放开我 不然我会连累你的！
Just let go, kid.
快放手 小子！
Bulkhead!
隔板！
I got you.
拉住你了
Arcee.
阿尔茜！
Fellow Deceticons, while our loyalty to Megatron's command has always remains steadfast,
各位霸天虎同僚 尽管我们对威震天一直是忠心耿耿
our leader's recent behavior has been questionable at best.
但统帅近期的种种行为实在难以服众
And it would seem as though Earth has become nothing short of a failed experiment.
而且如各位所见 地球不过是个失败的试验品罢了
Commander Airachnid, you're not suggesting that we abandon Lord Megatron?
毒蜘蛛指挥官 你不是想说 我们该抛弃威震天陛下吧？
Despite Soundwave's efforts, we have been unable to detect our master's signal.
尽管声波一再努力 我们仍无法搜索到主人的信号
Megatron is either permanently off-line or in the thrall of Unicron,
威震天不是一命呜呼 就是被宇宙大帝吞并
neither is in the best interest of the Decepticons.
无论如何 这对于霸天虎都非常不利
So I am deeming an exodus to be the most prudent cause of action,
所以我认为 及时撤军才是万全之策
unless anyone has a problem with that.
除非有人提出异议
Set course for Regulon Four.
向瑞特兰四号星球出发
You have something to say, Soundwave?
你有话要说吗 声波？
I command this vessel. You will resume your post.
这艘船由我指挥 请你坚守岗位
Step aside!
给我让开！
Oh...
噢…
I'll tear out your spark for that!
我要扯出你的火种下酒！
I yield.
我服了
Watch out for the quiet ones.
当心这种闷骚型的
Communication links are down, as expected.
通讯链失灵 这在预料之中
But we've lost their signal.
可连他们的信号也跟丢了
Doesn't that mean...
那岂不是…
Usually. But a more likely explanation would be the severe interference caused by these eletromagnetic anormalies.
这不足为怪 但更合理的解释是 电磁异常现象对信号造成了严重的干扰
So if we can't track them and they can't contact us...
要是我们找不到他们 他们也没法找我们…
How are we gonna know when they're ready for pick up?
我们怎么知道 该什么时候接头？
Where did you get that?
那个是谁给你的？
Optimus. Honestly, I don't know why he gave me the key to the ground bridge power supply.
擎天柱 老实说 我也不知道他干嘛要把环陆桥电源的钥匙给我
Jack, there is no key to the ground bridge.
杰克 环陆桥没有钥匙
Well then, what is this?
那好吧 这是什么？
That is the key to Vector Sigma.
那是魔力神球之匙
The what?
什么？
You're holding one of Cybertron's most important relics.
你手中的是塞博特恩最重要的文物之一
I shouldn't have this.
我何德何能…
Optimus entrusted it to you, Jack.
这是擎天柱托付给你的 杰克
But that doesn't make any sense, why?
可我怎么都想不通 为什么？
Because he doesn't plan on coming back.
因为他没打算活着回来
Megatron, do what I command.
威震天 听我号令
Destroy the Prime!
消灭那个领袖！
Megatron!
威震天！
Unicron's spark lies just beyond.
宇宙大帝的火种就在那后面
How do we get inside?
我们怎么进去？
By fooling Unicron's defenses into believing we're not a threat.
骗过宇宙大帝的防御机制 让它认为我们不构成威胁
Autobots, I will need you to keep our attackers at bay for as long as you can.
汽车人 我需要你们尽量拖住攻击者 越久越好！
We got to hold fast, for Optimus.
我们得撑住 为擎天柱拼了！
Optimus, swiftly.
擎天柱 快上！
Megatron.
威震天
Destroy the Prime. I command you.
消灭那个领袖 这是命令
Megatron is commanded by no one!
我威震天决不听命于任何人！
- Earthquake! - Take cover!
- 地震！ - 快找掩护！
Matrix of leadership, I call upon you.
领导模块 拜托你了！
You cannot defeat me, disciple of Primus. I have transcended physical being.
你无法打败我 原始天尊的门徒 我已是超越现实的存在！
By my will alone, all upon this world shall fall into chaos.
仅凭我的旨意 整个世界就可陷入无底深渊！
Not while I still function, Unicron.
只要我活着 你就休想 宇宙大帝！
The power of the Matrix will light our darkest hour!
领导模块之力将照亮我们最黑暗的时刻！
No!!
不！！
There could be aftershocks.
可能还有余震
Do you think...
你觉得他们…
I do.
肯定在
Yeah! Hoo-ya!
耶！呼呀！
Yes!
太棒了！
Teamwork, huh?
这也叫团队合作？
Where are we, Megatronus?
（Megatronus 震天威 元祖十三金刚中的堕落金刚的本名)
Don't you remember, old friend?
你忘了吗 老朋友？
Optimus, are you OK?
擎天柱 你还好吗？
Why did he call me that?
他干嘛那么叫我？
What did you do to him?
你把他怎么了？
Who are they?
他们是谁？
Our mortal enemies.
是我们的死敌！
We are outnumbered. Go, I'll cover you.
我们寡不敌众 快走 我掩护你！
Arcee.
阿尔茜
I was worried, Bulk.
我担心死了 小隔
You alright, Bee?
你没事吧 小蜂？
And Optimus? Is he...
擎天柱呢？他是不是…
Dead? No.
死了？没有
But he looked right at us without recognizing us, didn't even know his own name.
但他把我们几个当成陌生人 连他自己的名字都忘了
When Optimus surrendered the Matrix of Leadership, he lost more than the collective wisdom of the Primes.
擎天柱释放领导模块之后 失去的不止是领袖们智慧的结晶
He lost his own memories.
还有他自己的记忆
Welcome back, Lord Megatron.
欢迎回宫 威震天陛下
At ease, Breakdown. That is no way to welcome a long-lost comrade.
放松 打击 不该这样对待一个失散多年的同志
Orion Pax is one of us.
奥利安・派克斯是我们的人！